The term 'augmented reality' was first coined in
1992 by thomas caudell and david mizell.
Two engineers worka on a simple see-through headset
that aided airplane engineers in complex wiring schematics.
According to their documentation, the
goal of augmented reality commonly abbreviated as
AR was to enable cost reductions and efficiency
improvements
in many of the human involved operations
in aircraft manufacturing.
We've been dreaming about
the potential of AR for a long time
and the history of the medium stretches
back before we even had a term for it
In fact AR shares a history with its technological
cousin virtual reality both virtual reality
or VR and AR share a common ancestor the sword of
damocles built in 1968.
The sword of damocles was created by computer scientist and researcher
ivan sutherland his goal was to
create the ultimate display a digital interface capable of
transforming the physical world.
The prototype was so heavy. It needed to be suspended from the
ceiling by a mechanical arm for all that hardware
It could only display basic wireframe rooms
that were barely explorable.
But it was one of humankind's first experiments into replacing
your real world with a digital reality since 1992.
Many people have sought to fulfill the vision
that sutherland wrote about over half a century ago.
The ultimate display would be a room within
which the computer can control the existence of matter.
A chair displayed in such a room would be
good enough to sit in handcuffs displayed in such
a room would be confining and a bullet displayed
in such a room would be fatal with appropriate
programming.
Such a display could literally be the
wonderland into which alice walked on the mobile
ar side again.
This is how most of the world will
experience augmented reality for the first time
In fact the rapid development of smartphones
has actually contributed to the growth of
the vr and ar industries.
That's because the same
components that make smartphones work gyroscopes.
Accelerometers miniaturized high-resolution
displays are also required for AR and VR headsets.
The high demand for smartphones has driven the
mass production of these components throughout
the past 10 years,
resulting in greater
hardware innovations and decreases in costs.
In the most basic sense AR is created using the
front and rear facing cameras on your phone.
You hold it up and your screen is able to display
digital objects and information integrated
within your real world.
Your phone can now act like
a portal to new worlds experiences and information.
Google's first foray into the ar space was
google glass a head mounted display that
took the form of smart glasses.
It is still used today in a variety of
enterprise applications after glass.
Google's next ar play was project tango.
Tango was a combination of custom software
and additional hardware for unique depth sensing
smartphones. Tango enabled phones could track
the world around them and as a result. We're
capable of rendering unique digital overlays
onto the real world in 2017. Google announced
AR core an evolution of the tango platform.
AR core is an application programming interface
or api for building and developing mobile AR.
Experience by the end of this course you'll
have familiarity with how augmented reality works
as well as basic workflows in ar core. It's a young
medium augmented reality. It is already being used
in a variety of different capacities. In this
section we'll look at a few of the most popular.
Let's begin with shopping because it integrates
seamlessly with the real world. AR has proven to
be a powerful medium for shopping and retail
air can let you try on a watch a shirt
or a new shade of makeup. All without ever leaving your
home but the top use case for AR shopping right now is
furniture according to a few major studies.
Furniture is the number one thing people want to
shop for with AR. It's tough to know if a thousand
dollar couch will be the right one for you.
If you aren't sure it'll fit right in your living
room or match your curtains, AR's unique ability
to work within the world around us makes it easy
to integrate digital versions of furniture right
inside your house unlike 2d images which force you
to imagine the object in your home.
AR makes full use of 3d space letting you see the furniture
at the exact size and dimensions of real life.
Major furniture retailers like ikea
and house have put ideas like this
into practice with the option to purchase
included directly within the application.
When it comes to business, AR core enables
experiences for many different kinds of
professional organizations.
Warehouses can build helpful navigations
and instructions for workers.
Architecture firms can display designs in 3d space.
Retailers can give customers novel ways to engage
with products and advertisers can reach consumers
with immersive campaigns and this is just the tip
of the iceberg.
The power of ar is that it
lets users build relationships with brands
inside their physical spaces rather than trapped
behind screens. One of the most obvious uses for
AR is social media and social sharing snapchat
was the first media platform to fully embrace AR.
The platform introduced lenses in 2015 building
off the popularity of filters these allowed users
to digitally augment and manipulate faces
including that famous rainbow vomiting lens.
Though many may not have thought of it this
way, it is a lightweight expression of AR.
Facebook also followed the lead with its own ar
camerafx platform google is working to develop
an intuitive platform for creating content for
social AR. Through AR stickers stickers allow users
to import animated and interactive 3d objects
for use in social media. Although the usability
is still being fully explored air devices and
smartphones are able to pull off some truly
one-of-a-kind entertainment experiences in
2016 pokemon go became the first viral ar game
since then we've seen the launch of similar games
from mainstream franchises like harry potter
the walking dead and ghostbusters and
we'll see many more in the coming years.
But location-based adventure games like these
are only one possible game application for AR.
We're also seeing development in genres
ranging from arcade to tabletop games
as well as some types of games
that have never existed before.
It's also worth noting that while pokemon go was
popular. It also wasn't full ars. It just overlaid
flat 2d images on the real world creatures
in that initial launch of pokemon go didn't
behave the way they would if they were actually in
your physical space instead they floated on your
screen and only looked properly embedded in the
environment if you line them up with the ground.
Demonstrating complex subjects is another one
of AR's greatest capabilities allowing learners
to engage with spatial content visualize right
in front of them to that end google launched an
AR application for education expeditions. AR is an
educational experience designed to help teachers
show students information with simple and engaging
ar visuals for example students can explore a
strand of dna inspect the statue of david or
even witness an intense category 5 hurricane.
Spatial learning allows students to engage with
3d content directly rather than having to imagine
it while reading a textbook google's expeditions.
AR is an educational experience designed to help
teachers show students information with augmented
reality and education is even a broader category
than the classroom. AR will allow us to create
training environments where we can measure and
incorporate information in real time. AR is already
used in medicine and that will only increase
as the technology matures doctors and nurses are
using air's enhanced visualization capabilities
to more successfully diagnose patients
plan procedures and execute treatment plans
3d visuals offer much more for these
doctors to learn in comparison to 2d
visuals and interactive 3d visuals like
the ones in AR experiences offer even more.
AR could one day replace traditional charts
or guide surgeons through complex operations.
One step at a time medical science is one of
the most exciting areas for ar to impact both
today and tomorrow the one thing all of these
arenas have in common is their need for new
and better AR content. That's where tools like air
core and future creators like you come into play.
Non-profits can use AR to help build brand
identity and encourage deeper engagement
around critical issues. For example, say an
organization wants to educate the public about
the impacts of climate change. They could give
a presentation in front of a few hundred people
or they could create an ar experience that
lets millions of smartphone users view
what their own backyards might look like
amid an extreme drought or flood allowing
audiences to see the real world effects of
systemic problems makes AR a powerful strategy
for non-profits and other social impact
organizations to enhance their messaging.
This week we will focus on the state of AR who's
behind it how effective is the technology what
hurdles need to be overcome where can I buy it.
These are the questions you'll learn in module 2.
There are a few basic rules that augmented reality
creators need to remember about the way objects
behave in AR. These behaviors are the key to
merging the real and digital world seamlessly.
The first of these behaviors is place stationary
ar objects need to stick to one point in a given environment.
This could be something concrete
such as a wall floor or ceiling or it could be
suspended somewhere in midair whatever the case
placing means these objects stay where they're
positioned even when users are in motion the
mug on your coffee table doesn't jump around
when you move your head if you look away. It's
right there when you look back again for AR to
maintain the illusion of reality digital objects
need to behave in the same way real ones do.
In addition to sticking wherever they are placed
in the real world, AR objects need to be able to
scale. Think about it like this when a car is
coming towards you from the distance.
It starts out small and gets bigger a painting viewed from
the side looks very different when you walk around
and face it head-on our physical distance from
a given object and our orientation around it
changes how they appear to us. A well-constructed
AR experience will incorporate objects that
are not only appropriately placed but will look
different if you stand right next to it.
Below it above it or view it from afar, this is scaling
together placing and scaling are what take AR
objects from digital novelties to assets that
could potentially replace real-world counterparts.
Occlusion refers to what happens when an image
or object is blocked by another move your hand
in front of your face like this you've just
occluded the computer screen with your hand.
However imagine if you moved your hand in front
of your face and the screen was still visible
You'd probably get a little concerned. AR objects
have to play by the rules of occlusion if we want
them to seem real. This means that AR hardware has
to not only understand where the object is in the
room but also its relative distance from the user
compared with any other object physical or digital.
Occlusion means hiding virtual objects behind
other virtual objects and ones in the real world
say you move behind a wall while using AR. If you
still see the AR objects it will break your sense
of immersion that sense of AR objects actually
being in the real world in the app seamless.
Occlusion requires constant recalibration as users
can move in any direction at any given moment
which is why it's one of the trickiest
aspects of building successful AR content.
We'll talk later about the
ways that this is currently
a technical constraint in mobile AR. That
developers need to consider in their apps
just like a real world object. Objects in AR need
to respond to different patterns of lighting to
make sense in our minds. The colors shading and
shadows cast by these objects all need to behave
properly both in the initial lighting of a scene
and in the case of a lighting change.
For example, if you dim the lights during an ar experience
then the ar objects should change in color and
shading appearance similarly if you move an object
around. The shadows need to move accordingly just
like they would in real life. AR objects need to
appear solid. This may sound obvious but it takes
conscious effort to achieve as you engage with
and ultimately create AR content keep this in mind.
AR objects should never overlap with real
world objects nor should they appear to
be floating in thin air, if they're not
something like an airplane or balloon.
If either of these missteps is in your
app, it will break immersion for your users.
The final component of realism context awareness
is the most difficult to achieve as we discussed
in the last video. AR hardware has to be aware
of essentially every single object in its
environment. It needs to understand that there
is a desk a chair and a table next to a bookcase.
A vase and a television and it needs to know
which of these items is taller shorter fatter or
wider than the others and how this changes when
the subject moves around in space. That's a lot
to track generating this awareness quickly and
without a drop in the digital object's fidelity.
Smoothness or functionality is one of the biggest
challenges facing AR creators today companies like
google are investing in software tools like
AR core to help address some of these issues.